Finding Aid to the Margaret Sanger papers SSC.MS.00138
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES VI. SUBJECT FILES, 1761-1969
  - Legal cases
    - Dorothea Palmer (Eastview case), 1955 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - M. Sanger's Portland arrest for selling Family Limitation, 1916 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - William Sanger, 1915 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Town Hall raid (Rublee hearing), 1921 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Sentences of birth control advocates, undated (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Supreme Court hearings, 1931-60 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Legislation
    - General, 1921-42 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Congressional hearings, 1924-32 (Box 80, Folder 4-5)
    - Congressional hearings, 1933-35 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Congressional Record, 1934; 1952 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - New York State Assembly, 1923 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Thomas Malthus and Malthusianism, 1832-1938 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Marriage, 1922-58 (Box 82, Folder 2-3)
  - Maternal health, 1886-1941 (Box 82, Folder 4-5)
  - Medicine, 1925-57 (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Menstruation and menopause, 1933-52 (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Mental hygiene, 1918-52 (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Midwives, 1936; 1960 (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Migrant workers, 1920-49 (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Population
    - Research and reports, 1929-56 (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Pamphlets, 1841-1962 (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Reprints, 1921-61 (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Periodicals, 1931-57 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Articles, 1928-69 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - League of Nations publications, 1926; 1927 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Addresses, 1944-68 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Population and Migration, Vol. II (University of Chicago, Norman Wait Harris Memorial Foundation, Reports of Round Tables), 1929 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Australia, 1920-23 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - England, 1888-1954 (Box 84, Folder 7-8)
    - France, 1921-29 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Germany, 1925; 1942 (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - India, 1935-52 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Italy, 1932; 1953 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Japan, 1950-60 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Puerto Rico, 1936; 1956 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Sweden, undated (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - Pregnancy, 1922-38 (Box 85, Folder 8-9)
  - Prostitution, 1914-31 (Box 85, Folder 10)
  - Psychology and psychoanalysis, 1919-45 (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Public health, 1924-44 (Box 86, Folder 2a-2b)
  - Religion
    - General, 1922-60 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Catholic church, 1920-58 (Box 86, Folder 4-7)
    - Catholic church, 1929-58 (Box 87, Folder 1-2)
    - Judaism, 1932-35 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Protestant, 1924-61 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Society of Friends, 1934; undated (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - National Clergymen's Advisory Council, 1929-34 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - "The Churchman", 1934-52 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - "Information Service" (publication of Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America), 1931-56 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Together Magazine (Methodist publication), 1960 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Clippings (views of the clergy), 1944-49 (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - Sex education
    - Early pamphlets, 1850-1924 (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - England, 1943-47 (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - Sweden (Maj-Briht-Bergstrom-Walau), 1946-68 (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - United States, 1904-51 (Box 88, Folder 1-2)
  - Sex offenses, 1939 (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Sterilization, 1926-62 (Box 88, Folder 4-5)
  - Venereal diseases, 1918-41 (Box 88, Folder 6-7)
  - Women's rights, 1891-1941 (Box 88, Folder 8)
- SERIES VII. PRINTED MATERIAL, 1863-1981
  The Periodicals subseries is sorted alphabetically by publication title; Newspaper clippings and magazine articles are chronological with separate files for a few specific subjects; and Books are arranged alphabetically by author.
  This series consists primarily of books and periodicals that were part of Margaret Sanger's personal library. There is also a collection of articles and newspaper clippings. The subject matter of this material reflects that of the rest of the Sanger Papers: birth control, population, eugenics, sex education, health, marriage, sexuality, and miscellaneous other topics.
  - Periodicals
    - Affiliates Bulletin (PPFA), 1952-61 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - The Antiseptic, 1911 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Biology and Human Affairs, 1947; 1949 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Birth Control Herald, 1925 (Box 89, Folder 5)
      [see also SERIES X. OVERSIZE]
    - Birth Control News Society for Constructive Birth Control, 1922-1940 (Box 89)
      [See also OVERSIZE.]
      - 3 bound volumes, 1922 to 1940 (Unspecified on shelf)
      - Unbound issues, 1935 to 1940 (Box 90, Folder 1-8)
    - Birth Control News, Volumes 8-13 (bound), 1929-1935 (Box 146)
    - Birth Control News (unbound issues), 1935-1940 (Box 90, Folder 1-3)
    - Birth Control Review, 1917-1937
      - Bound volumes, 1917-1937 (Unspecified Reading Room shelves)
      - Unbound issues, 1938-1940 (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - The Birth Control Review, 1917-1919 (Box 142)
    - The Birth Control Review, 1922-1923 (Box 139)
    - The Birth Control (Japanese), 1933; 1952 (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - The Bulletin (Birth Control Federation of America, Inc.), June 1940 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Channels (National Publicity Council for Health and Welfare Service), 1943 (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Eugenical News, 1916-1939 (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Eugenical News (later Eugenics Quarterly), 1940-49 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Eugenics, 1929-31 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Eugenics Quarterly (formerly Eugenical News), 1954-1967 (Box 91, Folder 4-5)
    - Eugensia (Mexico), 1943-45 (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Family Planning (The Family Planning Association, London), 1952-76 (Box 92, Folder 1-3)
    - Family Planning News (India), 1960-61 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Family Planning News (Japan), 1961 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Family Planning/Population Reporter, 1972-81 (Box 93, Folder 3-5)
    - Grande Reforme, 1933-39; 1947; 1949 (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - Hamdard-I-Sehat, July 1939 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Holland-Rantos Monthly Press Clipping Service, 1941-47 (Box 94, Folder 2-4)
    - Human Fertility (formerly Journal of Contraception) (bound volumes), 1935-45 (Box 94)
    - Human Fertility (formerly Journal of Contraception) Volumes 5-10 & 12-13(bound), 1940-1948 (Box 146)
    - Indian Medical Journal, May 1952 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Information Service (Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America), 1931 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - The Japan Planned Parenthood Quarterly, 1950-55 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Journal of Contraception, Volumes 1-4 (bound), 1935-1939 (Box 146)
    - Journal of Contraception (Box 95)
      see Human Fertility
    - The Journal of Family Welfare, Family Planning Association of India, 1955-75 (Box 95, Folder 4-5)
    - The Journal of Family Welfare, 1976-85 (Box 96, Folder 1-3)
    - Journal of Heredity, 1946-49 (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - The Journal of Sex Education, 1949-52 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - The Journal of Social Hygiene, 1940-47 (Box 97, Folder 2-4)
    - Living, 1940 (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - Lucifer the Light Bearer, 1897-1906 (Box 98-99a)
      [See also SERIES X. OVERSIZE for 1886-1894]
    - Madras Birth Control Bulletin, 1932-38 (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Malaysian Medical Journal, 1936-37 (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - The Malthusian (entitled The New Generation, 1922-49), 1915-52 (Box 101-103)
    - Marriage and Family Living, 1941-52 (Box 104, Folder 3-5)
    - Marriage Hygiene (3 bound volumes), 1934-37 (Box 104)
    - Marriage Hygiene, Volume 2, 1935-1936 (Box 147)
    - Marriage Hygiene, Volumes 3-4, 1936-1937 (Box 147)
    - La Maternite Heureuse, 1956-60 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - Medical Woman's Journal, March 1943 (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - Medicina de Hoy (Cuba), 1937-38 (Box 105, Folder 3)
    - The Mother (The American Committee on Maternal Welfare), 1941 (Box 105, Folder 4)
    - Mother & Child (National Council for Maternal and Child Welfare, London), May 1941 (Box 105, Folder 5)
    - National Life, 1929-1931 (Box 105, Folder 6)
    - Die Neue Familie, 1950-1959 (Box 105, Folder 7-21)
    - The New Generation (Box 104)
      see The Malthusian
    - Peking Review, 1958 (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - People, April 1931 (Box 106, Folder 2)
    - Planned Parenthood Bulletin/Family Planning Monthly Bulletin (Family Planning Association of India), 1953-80 (Box 106, Folder 3-7)
    - Planned Parenthood Federation of America, Inc. News Letter, May 1942 (Box 106, Folder 8)
    - Planned Parenthood News (Chicago), 1947-61 (Box 106, Folder 9)
    - Planned Parenthood News (PPFA), 1952-64 (Box 106, Folder 10)
    - Planning, 1954-55 (Box 106, Folder 11)
    - Population: Journal of the International Union for theScientific Investigation of Population Problems, June 1933 (Box 106, Folder 12)
    - Population: Revue Trimestrielle de L'Institut National D'Etudes Demographiques, January - March 1956 (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Le Probleme Sexuel, 1933-35 (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Sexology, 1954; 1956 (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - Vox Medica (Germany), 1920 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Vox Studentium: The International Student Magazine, 1927 (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - The Woman Rebel, 1914 (Box 107)
      [see SERIES X. OVERSIZE--Sanger library and oversize box 129]
    - World Peace through Spiritual Regeneration, 1935-39 (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper clippings and magazine articles
    - 1920-40 (Box 108, Folder 1-2)
    - 1938 (rhythm method) (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - 1939 (Englewood, NJ school issue) (Box 108, Folder 4)
    - 1941-49 (Box 108, Folder 5)
    - 1944 (Box 108, Folder 6)
    - 1947 (Box 108, Folder 7)
    - 1947 (doctor's dismissal) (Box 108, Folder 8)
    - 1950-66 (Box 108, Folder 9-12)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted (Box 109, Folder 1-3)
    - Undated (Box 109, Folder 4)
    - Cartoons (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - John F. Kennedy nomination controversy (Box 109, Folder 6)
    - Japan (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - Frontspiece from book in Sanger's library: The Way of the Pilgrim, by R.M. French, 1930 (Box 109, Folder 8)
  - Books from M. Sanger's library
    - Allen, Adventurous Americans, 1932 (Box 136)
    - Andrews, Meet Your Ancestors, 1945 (Box 133)
    - Anonymous, Mixed Marriage, 1930 (Box 136)
    - Aptekar, Anjea, 1931 (Box 133)
    - Auken, Unge Kvinders Sexuelle Adfaerd, 1953 (Box 133)
    - Balfour, Evans, Notestein, Taeuber, Public Health and Demography in the Far East, 1955 (Box 135)
    - Barrett, Conception Control, 1922 (Box 133)
    - Baskin, Woman Rebel, 1976 (Box 140)
    - Bebel, Woman and Socialism, 1910 (Box 133)
    - Bell, The Sex Complex, 1920 (Box 133)
    - Besant, Autobiographical Sketches, 1885 (Box 133)
    - Bonar, Malthus and His Work, 1924 (Box 133)
    - Borrie, Population Trends and Policies, 1948 (Box 133)
    - Borsook, Vitamins: What They Are and How They Can Benefit You, 1941 (Box 133)
    - Bridges, The Fine Art of Marriage, 1930 (Box 133)
    - Burch and Pendell, Population Roads to Peace or War, 1945; 2 Volumes (2 copies of this title exist in Box 133) (Box 133)
    - Cape, Preparation for Marriage, 1932 (Box 133)
    - Carr-Saunders, Eugenics, 1926 (Box 141)
    - Carr-Saunders, The Population Problem, 1922 (Box 133)
    - Caton, The Key of Progress: A Survey of the Status and Conditions of Women in India, 1930 (Box 133)
    - Chachuat, Le Mouvement du "Birth Control" Dans Les Pays Anglo-Saxons, 1934 (Box 133)
    - Charles, The Practice of Birth Control, 1932 (Box 134)
    - Charles, The Sexual Impulse, 1935 (Box 134)
    - Child, Love and Unlove, 1921 (Box 142)
    - Cleland, The Population Problem in Egypt, 1936 (Box 134)
    - Clouston, New Tracts for the Times: Morals and Brain, 1912 (Box 134)
    - Coigney, Margaret Sanger: Rebel With a Cause, 1969 (Box 134)
    - Commander, The American Idea, 1907 (Box 134)
    - Coulter, The Evolution of Sex in Plants, 1914 (Box 134)
    - Cox, The Problem of Population, 1923 (Box 134)
    - Crackanthorpe, Population and Progress, 1907 (Box 134)
    - Damon, I Learned about Women from Them, 1962 (Box 134)
    - Darwin, What Is Eugenics?, 1929 (Box 134)
    - Davies, New Elementary Algebra, 1863 (Box 134)
    - Davis, The Population of India and Pakistan, 1951 (Box 134)
    - Dawson, Aggression and Population, 1946 (Box 133)
    - Day, The Evolution of Love, 1954 (Box 134)
    - De Beauvoir, The Second Sex, 1953 (Box 134)
    - Delisle, Francois, 1962 (Box 135)
    - Delisle, Friendship's Odyssey: The Autobiography of Francois Delisle and the Story of Havelock Ellis from 1916 to 1939, 1946 (Box 135)
    - Delisle, Friendship's Odyssey: In Love with Life, 1964 (Box 135)
    - Dennett, Birth Control Laws, 1926
    - Dickenson and Bryant, Control of Contraception, 1931; 2 Volumes (There exist two copies of this title in box 135.) (Box 135)
    - Dock, Hygiene and Morality: A Manual for Nurses and Others, Giving an Outline of the Medical, Social, and Legal Aspects of the Venereal Diseases, 1910 (Box 136)
    - Domon, Hiroshima, 1958 (Box 144)
    - Drucker and Hexter, Children Astray, 1923 (Box 135)
    - Drysdale, The Small Family System, 1917 (Box 135)
    - Dublin, Population Problems in the United States and Canada, 1926 (Box 137)
    - Durand-Wever, Die Verhutung Der Schwanger-Schaft, 1931 (Box 133)
    - Elgstrom, Tidens Kvinnor, 1944 (Box 135)
    - Ellis, Studies in the Psychology of Sex, Volume 6, Sex Relation to Society, 1911 (Box 135)
    - Everett, The Hygiene of Marriage, 1932; 2 Volumes (There are 2 copies of this title in this box.) (Box 136)
    - Fairchild, The Melting Pot Mistake, 1926 (Box 136)
    - Fairchild, People: The Quantity and Quality of Population, 1939 (Box 136)
    - Fielding, Birth Control in Asia: A Report of a Conference Held at the London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine, November 24-25, 1933, 1935 (Box 134)
    - Fielding, Parenthood: Design or Accident? A Manual of Birth Control, 1928 (Box 133)
    - Fielding, Sanity in Sex, 1920 (Box 136)
    - Fishbein and Burgess, Successful Marriage, undated (Box 135)
    - Florence, Birth Control on Trial, 1930 (Box 136)
    - Frank, Personal Counsel, 1946 (Box 136)
    - Freeman, Social Decay and Regeneration, 1921 (Box 136)
    - Fyfe, Revolt of Women, 1933 (Box 136)
    - Gallichan, The Psychology of Marriage, 1918 (Box 136)
    - Goldstein, The Meaning of Marriage, 1940 (Box 135)
    - Gorst, Race and Sex Booklets: Education and Race-Regeneration, 1913 (Box 138)
    - Haire, Birth-Control Methods, 1936 (Box 135)
    - Haire, Some More Medical Views on Birth Control, 1928 (Box 137)
    - Haldane, Heredity and Politics, 1938 (Box 136)
    - Hall, Life, and Love, and Peace, 1909 (Box 137)
    - Hamilton, A Research in Marriage, 1929 (Box 137)
    - Hartley, Sex Education and National Health, 1920 (Box 137)
    - Hersey, Margaret Sanger: Birth Control Pioneer, 1938 (Box 140)
    - Himes, Medical History of Contraception, 1936 (Box 137)
    - Holmes, Marriage and Divorce, 1913 (Box 137)
    - Holmes, The Trend of the Race, 1921 (Box 138)
    - Hooker, The Laws of Sex, 1921 (Box 138)
    - Horton, New Tracts for the Times: National Ideals and Race-Regeneration, 1912 (Box 137)
    - Huhner, Disorders of the Sexual Function, 1917 (Box 138)
    - Huxley, The Stream of Life, 1926 (Box 137)
    - Ingram, Sexual Morality, 1922 (Box 138)
    - International Labour Office, Migration Laws and Treaties, Volume I: Emigration Law and Regulation, 1928 (Box 138)
    - Japanese text (small), undated (Box 140)
    - Japanese text (large), 1960 (Box 140)
    - Jennings, The Biological Basis of Human Nature, 1930 (Box 137)
    - Johnsen, Birth Control, 1925 (Box 138)
    - Journal of the Mount Sinai Hospital, New York, Volume 10, Number 1, May-June 1943 (Box 137)
    - Key, The Century of the Child, 1909 (Box 138)
    - Key, Love and Ethics, 1911 (Box 138)
    - Kollwitz and Crede, Volk in Not!, 1927 (Box 137)
    - Kopp, Birth Control in Practice, 1933 (Box 137)
    - Korner, Fammtliche Berte, undated (Box 137)
    - Krafft-Ebing, Psychopathia Sexualis, undated (Box 134)
    - Ladies Review (in Japanese), undated (Box 138)
    - Lamson, My Birth: The Autobiography of an Unborn Enfant, 1916 (Box 138)
    - Latz, The Rhythm, undated (Box 138)
    - Laughlin, Eugenical Sterilization in the United States, 1922 (Box 137)
    - Lewin and Gilmore, Sex Without Fear, 1950; 2 Volumes (There exist two copies with this title in this box.) (Box 138)
    - Library of Congress catalogues
    - Lloyd, The Karezza Method or Magnetation: The Art of Connubial Love, undated (Box 138)
    - Lorimer and Osborn, Dynamics of Population, 1934 (Box 138)
    - Lorimer, Winston, and Kiser, Foundations of American Population Policy, 1940 (Box 138)
    - Lyttelton, The Christian and Birth Control, 1929 (Box 138)
    - Marchant, Birth Rate and Empire, 1917 (Box 139)
    - Meisel-Heiss and Robinson, The Sexual Crisis, 1917 (Box 139)
    - Merckx, The Bolshevism of Sex: Femininity and Feminism, 1921 (Box 139)
    - Meyer, New Tracts for the Times: Religion and Race-Regeneration, 1912 (Box 139)
    - Moore, The Case Against Birth Control, 1931 (Box 139)
    - Nomad, Sex: The Unknown Quantity, 1916 (Box 136)
    - Old Moore's Almanack, 1928 (Box 139)
    - Olivetti, Il Controllo Delle Nascite, 1957 (Box 139)
    - One page from Cecil Palmer and Hayward book (Box 139)
    - Parker and Watson, National School Series: National Fourth Reader, 1866(?) (Box 139)
    - Parliamentary Debates: House of Commons Official Report, Volume 329, Number 25, 1937 (Box 139)
    - Pater & Landau, What They Said in 1937: The Yearbook of Oral Opinion, 1938 (Box 139)
    - Pierpont, International Birth Control Conference: Report of the Fifth International Neo-Malthusian and Birth Control Conference, 1922 (Box 140)
    - Pitt-Rivers, Problems of Population: Proceedings of the International Population Union, 1932 (Box 137)
    - Problems of the Pacific: Proceedings of the Second Conference Institute of Pacific Relations, Honolulu, 1927 (Box 135)
    - Proceedings of the International Congress on Population and World Resources in Relation to the Family, 1948 (Box 137)
    - Pugh, The Great Unborn: A Dream of To-Morrow, 1918 (Box 139)
    - Raleigh, Woman and Superwoman, 1916 (Box 139)
    - Ramus, Marriage and Efficiency, 1922 (Box 139)
    - Robie, A Commonplace Life, undated (Box 140)
    - Robinson, Birth Control or the Limitation of Offspring, 1916 (Box 140)
    - Robinson, Eugenics and Marriage, 1917 (Box 142)
    - Robinson, Pioneers of Birth Control, 1919 (Box 139)
    - Robinson, Practical Eugenics, 1912 (Box 140)
    - Robinson, Seventy Birth Control Clinics: A Survey and Analysis Including the General Effects of Control on Size and Quality of Population (pamphlet), 1930 (Box 139)
    - Robinson, Seventy Birth Control Clinics: A Survey and Analysis Including the General Effects of Control on Size and Quality of Population (book), 1930 (Box 140)
    - Robinson, Woman, 1922 (Box 140)
    - Rout, Safe Marriage, 1922 (Box 142)
    - Royal Commission on Population Report, 1949 (Box 139)
    - Royden, Sex and Common Sense, 1922 (Box 140)
    - Rutgers, Eugenics and Birth Control, 1923 (Box 137)
    - Sanger, The Case for Birth Control, 1917; 3 Volumes (There are three copies with this title in this box.) (Box 139)
    - Sanger, Die Neue Mutterfchaft, 1927; 2 Volumes (There exist two copies of this title in this box.) (Box 141)
    - Sanger, Happiness in Marriage, 1926; 2 Volumes (There exist two copies with this title in this box.) (Box 142)
    - Sanger, History of Prostitution, 1897 (Box 141)
    - Sanger, Margaret Sanger: An Autobiography, 1938; 3 Volumes (There exist three copies of this title in this box.) (Box 141)
    - Sanger, Motherhood in Bondage, 1928; 2 Volumes (There exist two books with this title in this collection, one in box 136 and one in box 142.) (Box 136, Box 142)
    - Sanger, My Fight for Birth Control, 1931; 2 Volumes (There exist two copies with this title in this collection, one in box 140, one in box 142.) (Box 140, Box 142)
    - Index to the First Edition (1931) of My Fight for Birth Control by Margaret Sanger (Box 139)
    - Sanger, The New Motherhood, 1922 (Box 142)
    - Sanger, The Pivot of Civilization, 1922 (Box 142)
    - Sanger and Stone, The Practice of Contraception, 1931; 3 Volumes (There exist three copies of this title in this box.) (Box 141)
    - Sanger, Proceedings of the World Population Conference, 1927 (Box 141)
    - Sanger, What Every Boy and Girl Should Know, 1925 (Box 140)
    - Sanger, What Every Girl Should Know, 1922; 3 Volumes (There exist three books with this title in this box, two published in 1922 and the other published in 1980.) (Box 140)
    - Sanger, What Every Mother Should Know, 1925 (Box 142)
    - Sanger, Woman and the New Race, 1920; 3 Volumes (There exist three copies with this title in this box.) (Box 142)
    - Sanger, Woman and the New Race (in Japanese), 1921 (Box 142)
    - Schnegg, Les Mille et Une Vues de la Suisse, 1926 (Box 145)
    - Sinclair, World's End, 1940 (Box 142)
    - Stalmey, Love, 1919 (Box 143)
    - Steiner, Sexualnot und Sexualreform: verhandlungen Der Weltiga Fur Sexualreform, 1931 (Box 141)
    - Stekel, Frigidity in Woman, Volume 1, 1926 (Box 143)
    - Stekel, Frigidity in Woman, Volume 2, 1926 (Box 143)
    - Stekel, Peculiarities of Behavior, Volume I, 1924 (Box 143)
    - Stekel, Peculiarities of Behavior, Volume 2, 1924 (Box 143)
    - Stockham, Karezza, 1903 (Box 143)
    - Stoddard, The Revolt Against Civilization, 1922 (Box 143)
    - Stone, Hos Lakaren Svar pa Sexualfrager Avlakarna, 1951 (Box 143)
    - Stone, Laakari Vastaa Sukupuolikysymyksiin, 1946 (Box 143)
    - Stone and Himes, Planned Parenthood, 1951 (Box 143)
    - Stopes, Married Love: A New Contribution to the Solution of the Sex Difficulties, 1918 (Box 143)
    - Stopes, Radiant Motherhood, 1920 (Box 143)
    - Stopes, Wise Parenthood: A Sequel to "Married Love" (booklet), 1918; 2 Volumes (There exist two copies of this title in this box.) (Box 143)
    - Stopes, Wise Parenthood: The Treatise on Birth Control for Married People. A Practical Sequel to "Married Love, 1928 (Box 144)
    - Storrow, Our Sisters in India, undated (Box 143)
    - Stowell, Sex for Parents and Teachers, 1921 (Box 144)
    - Swinburne, Population and the Social Problem, 1924 (Box 143)
    - Thompson, Plenty of People, 1944 (Box 144)
    - Thompson, Science for War and Peace Series: Plenty of People, 1944
    - Thomson, The Control of Life, 1921 (Box 144)
    - Thomson, What is Man?, 1924 (Box 144)
    - Thorton, How to Achieve Sex Happiness in Marriage, 1939 (Box 144)
    - Todd, Easier Motherhood: A Discussion of the Abolition of Needless Pain, 1931 (Box 144)
    - Valabregne, Controle Des Naissances et Planning Familial, 1960 (Box 144)
    - Van de Velde, Ideal Marriage, 1928 (Box 144)
    - Van de Velde, Sex Hostility in Marriage, 1931 (Box 144)
    - Walker, The Traffic in Babies, 1918 (Box 143)
    - Washburn, So You're Going to Have a Baby, 1933 (Box 144)
    - Weill-Halle, La Grand Peur d'Aimer: Journal d'Une Femme Medecin, 1960 (Box 144)
    - Wexberg, The Psychology of Sex, 1931 (Box 144)
    - Wile and Day Winn, Marriage in the Modern Manner, 1929 (Box 144)
    - Winter, Der Mensch von Morgen, undated (Box 143)
    - The Woman Rebel (reprint of originals in bound volume)
    - Wright, Contraceptive Technique, 1951 (Box 144)
    - Yarros, Modern Woman and Sex, 1933 (Box 144)
    - The Third International Conference on Planned Parenthood: Report of the Proceedings, 1952
    - The Third International Conference on Planned Parenthood, 1952 (Box 138)
    - The Fifth International Conference on Planned Parenthood, 1955 (Box 137)
    - The Sixth International Conference on Planned Parenthood; Report of the Proceedings, 1959; As of 2018, the physical location of this volume could not be ascertained.
- SERIES VIII. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS, 1935-1993
  Research copies of audiovisual materials available in separate box.